[
  {
    "question": "What is the data bus size of 8086 processor?",
    "choices": [
      "16",
      "8",
      "32",
      "64"
    ],
    "answer": "16"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the maximum number of addressable memory of a processor that has a 20 bits of address bus lines?",
    "choices": [
      "102400",
      "1048676",
      "10240",
      "1048576"
    ],
    "answer": "1048576"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the maximum number of addressable memory (in English) of a processor that has a 20 bits of address bus lines?",
    "choices": [
      "4MB",
      "2MB",
      "1MB",
      "8MB"
    ],
    "answer": "1MB"
  },
  {
    "question": "This the first sequence of  a write memory operation.",
    "choices": [
      "2. MM reads the data stored at that address and sends it to the CPU.",
      "Data is written at desired location.",
      "CPU sends address of the desired location to the MM, together with the data to be stored into that location.",
      "CPU sends address of the desired location."
    ],
    "answer": "CPU sends address of the desired location to the MM, together with the data to be stored into that location."
  },
  {
    "question": "A word of data will consume two consecutive memory addresses.",
    "choices": [
      "false",
      "true"
    ],
    "answer": "true"
  },
  {
    "question": "Fetch instruction is an instruction for transferring the data from CPU to main memory.",
    "choices": [
      "False, it should be execute instruction.",
      "False, it should be main memory to CPU",
      "This statement is really true.",
      "False, it should be CPU to accumulator."
    ],
    "answer": "False, it should be main memory to CPU"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Read/Fetch Cycle: , the CPU sends address of the desired location then the Main Memory reads the data stored at that address and sends it to the CPU.",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "answer": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the Write/Store Cycle the CPU sends address of the desired location to the MM, together with the data to be stored into that location then Data is written at desired location.",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "answer": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "a word consumes two consecutive memory addresses. Similarly, a double word consumes four consecutive memory locations.",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "answer": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "Accessing 32 bit quantities always takes at least one memory operations on the 16 bit processors.",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "answer": "False"
  },
  {
    "question": "It is the fourth operating steps between the  cpu and memory operations.",
    "choices": [
      "The contents of the PC are transferred to the MAR (which are automatically transmitted to the MM) and a Read signal is\tsent to the MM.",
      "PC is set to point to the first instruction of \tthe program (the operating system loads the memory address of the first instruction).",
      "The addressed word is read out of MM and loaded into the MDR.",
      "The contents of MDR are transferred to the IR.  The instruction is ready to be decoded and executed."
    ],
    "answer": "The contents of MDR are transferred to the IR.  The instruction is ready to be decoded and executed."
  },
  {
    "question": "It is the fifth operating steps between the  cpu and memory operations.",
    "choices": [
      "During execution, the contents of the PC are incremented or updated to point to the \tnext instruction.",
      "The contents of MDR are transferred to the IR.  The instruction is ready to be decoded and executed.",
      "The contents of the PC are transferred to the MAR (which are automatically transmitted to the MM) and a Read signal is\tsent to the MM.",
      "The addressed word is read out of MM and loaded into the MDR."
    ],
    "answer": "During execution, the contents of the PC are incremented or updated to point to the \tnext instruction."
  },
  {
    "question": "In one of the component of CPU, what does MDR means?",
    "choices": [
      "Main Data Register",
      "Memory Data Register",
      "Memory data Record",
      "Main Data Record"
    ],
    "answer": "Memory Data Register"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the von neumann architecture the data bus is unidirectional.",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "answer": "False"
  },
  {
    "question": "It is a special segment register that is used for the LIFO stack.",
    "choices": [
      "Code Segment",
      "Stack Segment",
      "Extra Segment",
      "Data Segment"
    ],
    "answer": "Stack Segment"
  },
  {
    "question": "Perform the operation of the given binary numbers.\n\n\n\n\n    0110 0010 1010 00002\n\n\n\n\n-   1001 1101 0110 00002\n\n\n\n\n    1100 0101 0100 00002\n\n\n\n\nWhat is the value of SF?",
    "choices": [
      "0",
      "undefined",
      "x",
      "1"
    ],
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "Perform the operation of the given binary numbers.\n\n\n\n\n    0110 0010 1010 00002\n\n\n\n\n-   1001 1101 0110 00002\n\n\n\n\n    1100 0101 0100 00002\n\n\n\n\nWhat is the value of AF?",
    "choices": [
      "0",
      "1",
      "x",
      "undefined"
    ],
    "answer": "0"
  },
  {
    "question": "Perform the operation of the given binary numbers.\n\n\n\n\n    0110 0010 1010 00002\n\n\n\n\n-   1001 1101 0110 00002\n\n\n\n\n    1100 0101 0100 00002\n\n\n\n\nWhat is the value of OF?",
    "choices": [
      "1",
      "x",
      "undefined",
      "0"
    ],
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the data bus size of 8088 processor?",
    "choices": [
      "16",
      "8",
      "32",
      "64"
    ],
    "answer": "8"
  },
  {
    "question": "Read operation will transfers the contents of a specific MM location to the CPU. The word in the MM will be changed.",
    "choices": [
      "true",
      "false"
    ],
    "answer": "false"
  },
  {
    "question": "Write memory operation will transfer a word of information from the CPU to a specific MM location. This  will not overwrite the former contents of that location.",
    "choices": [
      "false",
      "true"
    ],
    "answer": "false"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many bits are there in a one double word of data?",
    "choices": [
      "64",
      "8",
      "16",
      "32"
    ],
    "answer": "32"
  },
  {
    "question": "To load a word requires two memory operations; to load a double word requires four memory operations in 8088 and 80188 processor.",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "answer": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "The 8088 and 80188 can manipulate word and double word values, even with their eight bit data bus.",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "answer": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "The 8086, 80186, 80286, and 80386sx processors have a 16 bit data bus. This allows these processors to access twice as much memory in the same amount of time as their eight bit brethren.",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "answer": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "It is a special segment register that contains the program or code.",
    "choices": [
      "Code Segment",
      "Stack Segment",
      "Extra Segment",
      "Data Segment"
    ],
    "answer": "Code Segment"
  },
  {
    "question": "It is a special purpose register that is also the program counter, it contains the memory address of the instruction to be executed.",
    "choices": [
      "instruction pointer",
      "Instruction Register",
      "Program counter",
      "flags register"
    ],
    "answer": "instruction pointer"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the data bus size of 80486 processor?",
    "choices": [
      "8",
      "64",
      "16",
      "32"
    ],
    "answer": "32"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the formula (2^n) to determine the  maximum addressable memory, what does n stands for?",
    "choices": [
      "number of bits of central bus",
      "number of bits of address bus",
      "number of bits of data bus",
      "number of bits of control bus"
    ],
    "answer": "number of bits of address bus"
  },
  {
    "question": "The control bus is an extensive collection of signals that control how the processor communicates with the rest of the system.",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "answer": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "The read and write control lines control the direction of data on the data bus.",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "answer": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "This the second sequence of  a read memory operation.",
    "choices": [
      "CPU sends address of the desired location to the MM, together with the data to be stored into that location.",
      "Data is written at desired location.",
      "CPU sends address of the desired location.",
      "MM reads the data stored at that address and sends it to the CPU."
    ],
    "answer": "MM reads the data stored at that address and sends it to the CPU."
  },
  {
    "question": "How many bits are there in a one byte of data?",
    "choices": [
      "16",
      "32",
      "8",
      "64"
    ],
    "answer": "8"
  },
  {
    "question": "In one of the component of CPU, what does IR means?",
    "choices": [
      "Instruction Register",
      "Instructional Register",
      "Instructional registration",
      "Instruction Registration"
    ],
    "answer": "Instruction Register"
  },
  {
    "question": "Von Neumann Architecture It is also known as the Stored Program Architecture or the Fetch-Decode-Execute Architecture.",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "answer": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "It is a special segment register that contains data referenced by almost all instructions and many addressing modes.",
    "choices": [
      "Stack Segment",
      "Code Segment Data Segment",
      "Data Segment",
      "Code Segment"
    ],
    "answer": "Data Segment"
  },
  {
    "question": "Perform the operation of the given binary numbers.\n\n\n\n\n\n          0010 0011 0100 0101\n\n\n\n\n    +  0011 0010 0001 1001\n\n\n\n\nWhat is the value ofCF?",
    "choices": [
      "1",
      "undefined",
      "x",
      "0"
    ],
    "answer": "0"
  },
  {
    "question": "For 8086 processor with address bus size of 20, what is the maximum addressable memory?",
    "choices": [
      "64GB",
      "1 MB",
      "16MB",
      "4GB"
    ],
    "answer": "1 MB"
  },
  {
    "question": "The 8088 and 80188 microprocessors have an eight bit data bus. This means that the CPU can transfer 16 bits of data at a time.",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "answer": "False"
  },
  {
    "question": "To access a word at an odd address requires two memory operations (just like the 8088/80188).",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "answer": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "It is a CPU component which  contains the memory address of the instruction to be executed.",
    "choices": [
      "IR",
      "MAR",
      "PC",
      "MDR"
    ],
    "answer": "PC"
  },
  {
    "question": "It is the number of address lines required to make 1024 memory addressable locations.",
    "choices": [
      "1024 bits",
      "20 bits",
      "24 bits",
      "10 bits"
    ],
    "answer": "10 bits"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many bits are there in a one word of data?",
    "choices": [
      "32",
      "16",
      "8",
      "64"
    ],
    "answer": "16"
  },
  {
    "question": "In one of the component of CPU, what does PC means?",
    "choices": [
      "Program Center",
      "Programmable Counter",
      "Program Control",
      "Program Counter"
    ],
    "answer": "Program Counter"
  },
  {
    "question": "The 8088 and 80188 cannot manipulate word and double word values, even with their eight bit data bus.",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "answer": "False"
  },
  {
    "question": "In the von neumann architecture the control bus is bidirectional.",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "answer": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "The IR (Instruction Register) contains the instruction that is being executed.",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "answer": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "The 80x86 family accesses a word and a double word by storing the low-order byte of a word at the address specified and the high-order byte at the next location.",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "answer": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "It is a CPU component which contains the data to be written or read out of the addressed location",
    "choices": [
      "IR",
      "MDR",
      "PC",
      "MAR"
    ],
    "answer": "MDR"
  },
  {
    "question": "It is a general purpose register  where most arithmetic and logical computations take place.",
    "choices": [
      "AX",
      "CX",
      "BX",
      "DX"
    ],
    "answer": "AX"
  },
  {
    "question": "The PC (Program Counter) contains the memory address of the instruction to be executed.  During execution, the contents of the PC are updated to point to the next instruction.",
    "choices": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "answer": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "It is a general purpose register that, as its name implies, counts things. It is often use it to count off the number of iterations in a loop or specify the number of characters in a string.",
    "choices": [
      "DX",
      "AX",
      "CX",
      "BX"
    ],
    "answer": "CX"
  }
]